

Chennai, India

# **Summary**

With 9 years of professional experience, skilled predominantly in Front end technologies. Keeps myself updated, communicates effectively, enjoys working in a team, as well as contributing individually, loves transparent feedbacks, quality code and CI/CD. Been to Paris for short-term.

Skills			
Frontend	JavaScript, React, Redux, TypeScript, SASS, React Native, GraphQL, Next.js, Webpack, Tailwind, Preact		
Backend	Node, Express JS, Java		
Dev Utils	Jest, Eslint, StyleLint, Cypress, Storybook, React Testing Library, Bootstrap, Material UI, Styled Components		
Other Tools	AWS, JIRA, Git, SonarQube, Kibana, NewRelic, Docker, Google Analytics, FireBase, Photoshop.		

## **Experience**

Oct 2019 – Present

# **Polyglot Power Programmer** - *Infosys*

Part of an elite unit under CTO, transforming business by leveraging latest tech stack, building MVP, architecture for teams using reusable components and microservices and train them to take it further.

2017 - 2019

Full Stack JavaScript developer - Renault-Digital

Web app used by auto engineers to view and plan ahead manufacturing and assembling of car parts in plants.

Role: To enable the team develop UI, API and to communicate with end users for planning of manufacturing parts in a car.

2016 - 2017

Full Stack developer - Cognizant Technology Solutions

Search tool customization with open source for **Pearson** Education.

Role: To enhance fast search functionality of Pearson clients with API based on ReactJS, Elasticsearch, Cassandra, Logstash, and Apache Nutch.

2014 - 2016 • **J2EE/UI Developer** - *Accenture* 

Tablet App for **Walmart** Stores employees to log hours.

Web Developer - Wipro Technologies
 Payment Management web portal, with Custom J2EE MVP framework in CITI-Group financials.

Free time • **Entrepreneur** - *DoPartTime.com* 

A PayPal incubated startup, also selected by Google Launchpad, which is a job web portal & mobile app for part time jobs with 3000+ active users.

## **Education**

Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science)	Karunya University	2007-2011
---	--------------------	-----------

### **Honors & Awards**

- Selected for Google Launchpad 2015, training and mentoring on mobile App development and design strategies by Google for Startups.
- Certificate of Excellence Ninja award for 2021 Q1 in Infosys.
- **Guinness Book of world Records** participant, for 18-hour coding marathon AppFest participation, by **Microsoft**.
- **Applause** award 2018 in **Renault** for automating Database hydration.
- Quarterly **Dynamo award 2016** for implementing open-source technology in **Cognizant** Technology Solutions.
- **Archimedes' Award** for automating manual efforts in Wipro Technologies.
- **SCJP** (Sun Certified Java Programmer) by **Sun Microsystems** (Oracle).
- 3<sup>rd</sup> prize in "Apps for Chennai" contest for developing mobile App "infoTap".
- Participated in **Google for Mobile** 2015, a technical meet-up conducted by **Google**.
- 4<sup>th</sup> place in **Cisco Net Rider's** Competition 2010 conducted throughout SAARC countries.
- Batch topper in Wipro training (Fast Track batch).